Nazia Hasan

nhasan1987@gmail.com +358405775010 linkedin.com/in/naziahasan uxfol.io/nazarahthecat Lohja, Uusimaa, Finland

UX Designer

I aim to align business goals and end user satisfaction while conceptualizing solutions. I enjoy working with developers to harmonize UX & implementation works. I have a **Master's degree** with **UX major** and relevant **professional experience** (5+ years). I love to face a challenge with empathy, focus on details and bringing uniqueness towards its solution.

Experience

UX Designer

Piceasoft Tampere, Finland January 2023 - Present

I design and evaluate processes and related interfaces that enable people to extend the lifecycles of their electronic and smart devices via different services in the circular economy.

Head of UX

Platform of Trust Tampere, Finland July 2019 - November 2022

Starting as a **DX Developer**, towards becoming a **Product Manager**, the **Design Lead** in **Concepts and APIs**, and in my last role, my focus was on data servitization and monetization field targeting build environment industry in Finland. I **managed product development** works and **ensured great Developer eXperience** for related company products. I also made a **design system** for developing company services.

UI/UX Designer

Sampo Software Oy Tampere, Finland June 2016 - January 2019

I worked on projects from diversified application fields (API management system, real-time monitoring of biomass equipment, and secured bike storage.) My work included doing **user research**, **wireframing**, to creating **low/mid fidelity prototypes**, **interaction model**, **usability evaluation**, and **user-onboarding**.

Senior Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Ohon Technology Itd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

May 2014 - August 2014

I took the responsibilities of **managing an offshore software quality assurance (SQA) team** of a USA based software firm.

Software Business Development Executive

TigerIT Bangladesh Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

October 2013 - April 2014

I worked in **tender procurement** for government and international ICT projects. I also composed **technical documentation** of company products and services.

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

SoftwarePeople Bangladesh

Dhaka Bangladesh

August 2011 - July 2013

I worked to **analyze requirements**, prepare and manage **test cases**, execute **manual** & **automated testing**, **track** bugs, etc.

Skills

Design	Development	Tools	Others
User research UI Design Prototyping Wireframing Usability evaluation	HTML CSS Low/no code OAS3 (Open API Specification 3)	Figma Sketch Miro Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop	Developer marketing Tech blogging Developer guides Product management SAFe 4.0 framework
Usage Studies Accessibility	React Gatsby	Voiceflow Azure APIM + DevOps Git Jira + confluence Stoplight	Finnish B1-B2 Al in UX

Education

Tampere university of Technology

Tampere, Finland | 2014 - 2018

Master's in Technology, User Experience

University of Dhaka

Dhaka, Bangladesh | 2005 - 2010

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Certification

UI Design Patterns for Successful Software - Interaction Design Foundation

Conducting Usability Testing - Intereaction Design Foundation

The Complete 'No Code' 'Developer Course - Udemy

REST API Design, Development & Management - Udemy

Information Architecture (IA) Fundamentals - Udemy

SAFe 5.0 Product Owner/ Product Managear - Scaled Agile Framework Certification Training

SAFe 4.0 Agilist - Scaled Agile Framework Certification Training

Introduction to Data Economy - Osaango Academy

Marketing for Developers - Osaango Academy

Essential APIs - Osaango Academy

Fix Your API Design and Documentation - Osaango Academy

Yleisten kieli tutkintojen suomen kielen keskitason tutkinto - Yleiset kielitutkinnot

The Elements of Web Design - Code School

Other Experiences

Podcast participant in "Women in API - Season 3", hosted by Spotlight

Podcast parcitipant in "Data Economy Female Success Stories", hosted by DataProduct Business Keynot speech on "Low/No code driven development - winning sales pitch with WOW EFFECT" at API Days Helsinki and North 2022.

Keynote speech on "API documentation and developer guide" at APIOps Helsinki, November 2020.

Hobbies

Cycling, flower bulb planting, Lego, boardgames and video games.

References

(on request)

Please don't hesitate to reach me if you would like to see some of my confidential works. Thanks!